Guide to the Douglas Crase and Frank Polach Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Douglas Crase papers, Series I
  - Other papers
    - Darragh Park, pencil drawing in frame., 1995 (Box 39 (Art))
      view from James Schuyler's window at Chelsea Hotel. In frame and inscribed to Douglas from Park, November 1995. The drawing was used for the cover of James Schuyler and Darragh Park's Two Journals (Tibor de Nagy Editions, 1995).
  - Audiovisual material, 1970-2010 (Box 85)
  - Electronic media, 1970-2010 (Box 87)
- Frank Polach papers, 1960-2012; Series II
  - F.P. Correspondence, 1970-2000 (Box 40)
    Abawi, Georges; Aldwinckle, Herb; Angell, Bobbi; Archibald, Jim; Ashbery, John; Barneby, Rupert to Frank Polach; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1976–80; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1981–84; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1985–87; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1988; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1989; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1991; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1990; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1992; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1993; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1994; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1995; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1996; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1997; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1998; Barneby—Frank Polach, 1999; Barneby—Frank Polach, 2000; Barneby, Rupert from Frank Polach; Barneby from Polach, 1990–91; Barneby from Polach, 1992; Barneby from Polach, 1993; Barneby, Rupert, 1994; Barneby, Rupert, 1990–1994; Barneby, Rupert, 1995–2000; Barneby—Frank Polach, misc. notes; Becker, Ronald; Bellringer, Sam; Botten, Elizabeth; Brown, Mark; Buck, Bill; Caparo, Willa; Carey, Tom; Charneski, Jason; Corbett, William; Cullen, Rosemary; Crase, Douglas, 1974; Douglas to Frank, 1974 (2 folders); Crase, Douglas, 1975 +; Douglas to Frank, 1975–76; Doug to Frank, 1977+; Crase, Douglas—Notes (4 folders); DWC Notes FP; Crase, Douglas from Frank Polach; Dash, Robert (4 folders); Duane, Tom
  - F.P. Correspondence, 1970-2000 (Box 41)
    França, Paulo + Wedding 5/01/11; Fraser, Susan; Greenberg, Evelyn and Ruth Weber; Grimes, James; Hawkins, John; Holmgren, Patricia & Noel; Hunter, James E.; Irwin, Dorothy; Kallunki, Jacquelyn; Kernan, Nathan; Kunst, Scott; Lipe, Clark; Litwin, Nancy; Long, Marie; Lord, Pamela; Luteyn, James; McCaffrey, Joseph; Malanga, Gerard; Moore, Harold (4 folders); Myers, Budd; North, Charles; Ossorio, Alfonso; Panayoti, Kelaidis; Park, Darragh; Pimentel, MJ; Piotrowski, Greg—"Rupert" daylily; Polach, Joseph (4 folders); Polach, Leah (Spillman); Price, Amanda; Puniello, Francoise; Rolen, Heather; Rosenthal, Deborah; Russo, Terese; Schuyler, James (4 folders); Schuyler, James and Douglas Crase drafts; Schuyler, James, misc.; Sims, Patterson; Slouth, Cecily; Taylor, Bob; Theirs, Barbara; Tibor de Nagy—Ripley receipts; Webster, Robert K.; Wellck, Michele; Wheeler, Don; Workman, Richard; Harry Ransom Center; Yau, John
  - Garden journals, 1995-2011 (Box 42)
    No. 1—1/23/94–9/2/95; No. 2—10/9/94–5/12/96; No. 3—5/15/96–4/30/97; No. 4—5/1/97–12/31/97; No. 5—1/1/98–8/31/98; No. 6—9/1/98–12/31/98; No. 7—Jan.–Aug. 1999; No. 8—Sept. + 1999; No. 9—Jan.–June 2000; No. 10—July 2000; No. 11—2001; No. 12—Jan.–Aug. 2002; No. 13—Sept.–Dec. 2002; No. 14—1/1/03–6/30/03; No. 15—7/1/03–12/31/03; No. 16—Jan.–June 2004; No. 17—July–Dec 2004; No. 18—Jan.–June 2005; No. 19—July–Dec. 2005; No. 20—Jan.–June 2006; No. 21—July 1 2006–Dec. 2006; No. 22—1/1/07–6/30/07; No. 22—7/1/07–12/1/07 + 9/1/08–12/31/08; No. 24—Jan. 1–Aug. 2008; No. 25—1/1/09–11/15/09; No. 26—11/16/09–7/31/10; No. 27—8/2010–9/2011; House, yard, garden photographs.
  - Subject files, 1969-2012 (Box 43)
    Wellston High School, 2012; Wellston High School, 2002, 2007; Vita; Publications; Reference Sources On Agriculture, 1979; Polach—First Thing About Houseplants, 1976; P. capsici; Pathogenicity of Phytophtore cactoru..., Sept 1975; June 1975—Occurrence and Biology of Botryotinia; June 1975—Infection of Beans by...; 1975—Benzimidazole resistance...; Apr. 1974—Fungus Resistance; Sept. 1973—...Dodine Tolerance in Venturia Inaequalis (empty folder); July 1972—Venturia Inaequalis...(abstr.); Jan. 1972—Phytophthora Capsici...; Sept. 1969—Diplodia natalensis...; Duplicates; NYBG (New York Botanical Garden); Morocco Rabat Library, 1990; Owl's Head, Maine; FP—DC-Local Issues; Chelsea; Pottery Barn; Chelsea, NYC, 1991–93; London Terrace pictures; London Terrace; Seminary, 1993; Prison 2/5 mtg.; Prison—Doug; Ancestry; Copyright; Copyright forms filed by Frank for works by Dwight Ripley and Rupert Barneby.; Guest menus; Chelsea and Carley Brook dinner menus.; Garden 2012; Garden 2011; Garden 2010; Garden 2009; Garden 2008; Garden 2007.
  - Subject files, 1960-1999 (Box 44)
    Published poems - "Home in the Rain" in James Schulyer and Charles North's Broadway: A Poets and Painters Anthology (1979). "Brave Like Their Fathers" in Poetry Now, 1978. "Small Craft Warnings" in The World, no. 32, 1979; Rutgers University Library - Multiple folders with items related to Frank Polach's employment at Rutgers University; New York Botanical Garden - Multiple folders with items related to Frank Polach's publications and employment at The New York Botanical Garden; Columbia—Appl.; College transcripts, etc. Transcripts, GAPSFAS, GRE. Who's Who in the East UCD Placement; 4-H, 1963; Genetics of Pathogenicity and Sexuality in Phytophthora capsici - Bound dissertation. University of California Davis, 1971.; Wellston High School Yearbook, 1962 - Frank is named "Mr. WHS" (outstanding senior).
  - Photographs, 1970-2000 (Box 45)
    Photographs, Doug and Frank (family, friends); Rupert's Loft and Kittay House; Doug and Frank professional photos; Both book party (binder and folder of proofs and negatives); Unlikely Angel at Poets House; Unlikely Angel: Snapshot survey of show; Friends and Family.
  - Papers relating to Robert Dash, 1974-1992
    - 16mm Film and color slides, 1976-1981 (Box 46)
      35 mm color slides (4 slide trays - "Deep Space", "Sagg '76, '77, '78", "Sagg 80–81", [untitled].
    - Robert Dash, "A Family Landscape", 1979; 1 (Box 86)
      A Family Landscape, 1980 - 16 mm film with sound. Chesebrough-Pond centennial promo filmed at Madoo in 1979. Includes scenes of Robert Dash painting. Filmscript by Douglas Crase.
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Photographs and clippings, 1974-1992 (Box 47)
      Photographs, 1974–1992 - Black & white and color snapshots, approx. 50 envelopes. Photographs were primarily taken at Robert Dash's home in Sagaponack, Long Island. Photographic negatives and contact sheets, ca. 1976–1997 Black & white and color negatives, 3 3-ring binders. Negatives and contact sheets primarily taken at Robert Dash's home in home in Sagaponack, Long Island. Also included are snapshots from Frank and Douglas' Chelsea and Carley Brook homes and elsewhere; Magazines and clippings - Approx. 10 magazines and assorted clippings about Robert Dash.
- Dwight Ripley papers, 1920-2009; Series III
  - Primary - Frank's Files, 1930-1975 (Box 48)
    Ripley, Dwight. Ripley, Dwight—NYBG archives (New York Botanical Garden). Ripley, Dwight—will. Ripley, Dwight—estate. Ripley, Dwight—misc. information; Ripley, Alice Louise; Ripley, Dwight—named plants; Ripley, Harry Dwight Dillon; Ripley art collection; Ripley—drawings & collectors; DR to Draguto (i.e., Rupert Barneby)—ca.1932. Handwritten 2 pp. letter.; DR letters to Rupert Barneby—1939–1941 transcribed; DR letters to RB—1939–1941; Dwight's will—1950; Ripley ltrs to J.T. Howell—California Acad. Science; DR—Iberian itinerary—1962; DR—etymology notes—ca. 1965–1970; DR letters to Geraldine Barneby; DR to Geraldine Barneby—12/05/1970; Ripley—list of tricks; Ripley—Memento Mori—SemiColon 1:1, p.3.; DR—misc. botanical notes; Ripley—miscellaneous lists; Ripley—financial statements; Ripley Realty Co; DR—Plaza Stationary; DR—stories; DR—poems in Polish; Ripley—Spring catalogue; Sunlit Scene—Part I; Sunlit Scene—Part II; Beach at Amagansett; Ripley to Willard Maas and—or Marie Menken (photocopies); Ripley to Marie Menken (photocopies); "Autobiography of Dwight Ripley" (photocopies); Ripley "going to the Ball" (photocopies); Woodlawn cem.—Ripley plot; Loria, Jeffrey—receipt of Pollacks sold by Rupert to pay estate taxes; Maas, Willard—poems, letter to RB, 1943–1944; Manrique, Cesar to DR & RB—–ca. 1966; Ripley, Dillon to Rupert Barneby—12/15/1975; Sandwith, Noel to RB 1965; Ruthven, Todd—1957; Photos of The Creeks—sent by Ossorio to Rupert; Maas, Willard to Ripley & Barneby; Menken, Marie to Ripley
  - Ripley research, 1950-2000 (Box 49)
    Tibor de Nagy Gallery Records - NY Archives: DR6. Washington Archives: DR7. re: James I. Merrill; Ripley Collection—Cal.Acad. of Sci. - Ripley Collect.: Cal. Academy of Sci.—DR25; Pocket Diaries—Iberian itinerary - Douglas Crase transcriptions; Ripley Letters—Ransom Center; DR—Art notices; Ripley Am. Rock Garden Soc .Bulletin; DR—Etymological dictionary; A list of plants at the Spinney; DR—Observations on Polish; DR Plaza stationary—notes & poems; Catania; Ripley Bkgrd; Background to DR—drawings; Cazorla Violet; Misc. plants in Both; Colored pencil; Color; Collectors—Dwight drawings; Drawing; Ripley family; Maps, etc.—(e.g. Los Angeles); Research leads; Ripley obits; Ripley—poems; Ripley—miscellaneous poems—copies; Record of species; Ripley—Impressions of Nevada; Ripley—Bibliogr. of publications; Ripley AGS bulletin; Species collected—Rupert & Dwight; Miro' Regalito; Marcel Le Piniec award; Union Pacific; Ripley Raisonné; Ripley—Species epithets; The Spinney; Tibor de Nagy—editions; Vasculum; Translation; CPI conversion table; DR funeral home; Greenhouse; Ripley, Harry grave—William Reid Dick - Ripley; Ripley, Harry—will; Blushing; Harrow; Surrogate's Court—letters testamentary—1974–1979; Surrogate's Court—final letters test'ry—1974–1979; Queer persecution in the 1950s; DR—Gleaves, Crawford—financial account; Unsorted.
  - Drawings, poetry, exhibition material, 1920-2009 (Box 50)
    Poetry London-New York, nos. 1–4, 1956–1960.;This journal, edited by Thurairajah Tambimuttu, was supported by Dwight Ripley. The cover of issue no. 3 is by Ripley; Later Drawings of Dwight Ripley (3-ring binder); Poems by Dwight Ripley (3-ring binder, photocopies and printouts); Tibor de Nagy Gallery: The First Fifty Years 1950–2000 (catalog); Arts Digest, Feb. 1, 1955.; With review of Ripley exhibition.; Surrealisme + Abstraction: Choix de la Collection Peggy Guggenheim = Surrealisme + Astractie: Keuze uit de Verzameling Peggy Guggenheimn, Palais des beaux-arts (Brussels); Stedelijk Museum (Amsterdam) [1951].; Dwight Ripley, Tibor de Nagy Gallery Announcement Cards, The Three Arts Announcement Cards, Tibor de Nagy 25th Anniversary Card and Statement (3-ring binder); Includes a pencil sketch of Rupert by Dwight (Oct. 1926), announcement cards and other ephemera from Art of This Century, The Three Arts, Tibor de Nagy Gallery, Willard Maas, Marie Menken, original drawings by pioneering animator Norman McLaren among other items.; Early Ripley Drawings (3-ring binder); Photographic documentation of Dwight's artwork includes photographs by Rudy Burckhardt.
  - Appointment books, 1941-1973 (Box 51)
    3 five year diaries and 10 "week-at-a-glance" calendars.
  - Artwork, 1950-1962
    - "Cabo de Gata,"1962, ink and colored pencil on paper in frame (Box 81 (Art))
      Dwight Ripley. "Cabo de Gata,"1962. Ink and colored pencil on paper in frame.
    - "Setúbal,"1962, ink and colored pencil on paper in frame (Box 80 (Art))
      Dwight Ripley. "Setúbal,"1962. Ink and colored pencil on paper in frame.
    - Framed artwork, 1950; 1951 (Box 82)
      Dwight Ripley. "Ponty and Pinty," 1950. Typewritten poem with ink and colored pencil drawing with collaged element in frame. The drawing is on the back of an order form from a New York City tea store on East 55th Street.; Dwight Ripley. "Boom, No.1," 1951. Ink and gouache on stationery in frame.
- Rupert Barneby papers, 1940-2000; Series IV
  - Primary - Frank Polach files, 1940-2000 (Box 52)
    Barneby—notes to—2000; Barneby—Air Force D.T.; Barneby Document—Living; Barneby—birth certificate; Barneby—certificate of arrival; Barneby—certificate of vaccination; Barneby classification— 3/14/48; Barneby cremation document; Barneby declaration of intention procedure, 2/24/42; Barneby, Rupert—healthcare policy; Barneby induction order, 3/19/42; Barneby—living will; Barneby, Rupert—Medicare; Barneby Documents—Living; Barneby—naturalization, 12/23/41; Barneby—petition for naturalization, 5/22/51; Barneby—power of attorney; Barneby—registration certificate; Barneby—documents—IDs; Barneby Documents—Death; Barneby—Certificate of death; Barneby—Community Funeral Society; Barneby—employment app. no.; Barneby—executor; Barneby—wills; Barneby—will, probate; Barneby Memorial program; Barneby—memorial program; Barneby, Rupert—obituaries; Smith Hill Cemetery; Barneby, other; Barneby, Rupert—Brittonia; Barneby legume catalog; Barneby, Rupert—NYBG archives; Barneby Rupert—Lower Brackhampton; Munz, Philip—Aquilegia barnebyi; Barneby, Rupert—ancestry; Barneby, Rupert—Archives of American Art; Barneby, Rupert—Myers, John B; Barneby, Rupert—New York Times; Barneby, Rupert—Parenthese; Barneby, R—Scott, Sir Peter; Barneby, Rupert—Sclater, P.L.; Barneby, Rupert—Stirling Houses; Barneby—Thomas Jernick, 8/20/74/shipping; Barneby—Trewyn Court; Stable NYBG; Barneby Family; Barneby, Geraldine—notes to R. Barneby; Barneby, Geraldine—estate; Barneby, Louisa—estate; Barneby, Philip—death certificate; NYBG, Orion, botany mags; Barneby, Rupert; RB—address book; Barneby awards, citations, letters of appointment; Barneby biblio ca. 1958/with handwr. additions; Barneby correspondents—response to Atlas of North Amer. Astragalus; Barneby correspondents—miscellaneous; Barneby MSS pages—Astragalus; RB—composition book—c. 1995–2000; Poems Barneby—most by Rupert! not DW; Barneby to Willard Mass (photocopy); Barneby to Marie Menken (photocopy); Barneby "A Little Alphabet" (photocopy).
  - Barneby research (Box 53)
    Barneby Chronology in RE FP & DC; Barneby Correspondence to FP & DC (notes in RE Ruperti I.); Barneby—Frank Polach notes of visits; Barneby obituaries; Barneby—civil papers copies; Barneby papers at NYBG; Buck, Bill—Barneby bibliography; Ruperti Imagines—exploratory notes; Ruperti Imagines—mailing list; Ruperti Imagines—correspondence; Barneby memorial; Barneby memorial—e-mail messages; Early letters to R.—NYBG library; Ripley-Barneby—litbiz; Hunt Institute exhibit: 2004-2005; Botany 2004—Barneby Colloquium; Smith Hill cemetery; Nevada, Utah etc.; Nevada test site; Rupert Barneby award; RB: list of places & dates, on Spinney sta.; Barneby in leaflets—biblio;; Marcel Le Piniec award (args); Cassia illustrations—by Bobbi Angell ;Barneby family (background)—"p"; RB Genealogy; Trewyn—Ludlow, Brockhampton, and other houses; Lower Brockhampton; Saltmarshe Castle; Wilcroft; Ludlow; Sugwas; Barney secondary—profiles, etcera; NYBG; Botanical Latin; Aliciella—Porter—(Gilia); Alpine Gardens & nurseries; Barneby, WSJ letter—re J.Bartlett Garden—Battery Park City; Cladistics; Taxonomy; Cymopterus ripleyi; Ash Meadows: Beatley—A. Phoenix: reveal; Astragalus; Ground observer corps—& UFOs.; Flora of Guianas letter; Sheltie; Castilleja barebyana—Aquilegia barnebyi—orig. papers; Barneby last books; Barneby correspondents—articles; RB's oral history of NYBG—F's notes; Barneby reviews of work; Rupert's name.
  - Photographs, circa 1941-1945 (Box 69)
    Rupert Barneby. "Astragalus striatiflorus," ca. 1943–44. Black and white photograph in frame.; "Astragalus striatiflorus M. E. Jones on dune beneath sandstone cliffs, near Kenab, Utah" is typewritten caption pasted on framed photograph. Rupert Barneby. "Cymopterus megacephalus," ca. 1941–45. Black and white photograph in frame.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Restricted Fragile, Glass.
  - Photographs and collages, 1940-1944 (Box 72 (Oversize))
    Rupert Barneby. "Gilia ripleyi" April 194o, graphite drawing in frame. According to personal correspondence with Douglas, this was "drawn in a motel near Death Valley in April 1940. It was the first new species Rupert and Dwight ever located, although Rupert was not able to publish its scientific description until 1942. By this time he had already published their finding of Cymopterus ripleyi, which thus became their first published new species. Both publications were in Leaflets of Western Botany. The Gilia had a special place in Rupert's heart. It has since been removed from the genus Gilia and renamed Aliciella ripleyi."; Rupert Barneby. "Self-Portrait," 1944. Collage in frame.; Rupert Barneby. "Portrait of Dwight Ripley," 1944. Collage in frame. "Self-Portrait" and "Portrait of Dwight Ripley" can be viewed as "family portraits." They are created in the style of French poet, critic and collagist Georges Hugnet.
    Restricted Fragile. Glass.
  - Photograph, 1941 (Box 73)
    "Cymopterus megacephalus M. E. Jones on talus under cliffs near Navajo Bridge, Coconino Co., Arizona" is typewritten caption pasted on framed photograph. Rupert Barneby. "Arctomecon humilis," ca. 1941. 3 black and white framed photographs. Also known as the Dwarf Bearclaw Poppy. Rupert and Dwight collected the plant in 1941 and 1942.
    restricted frigile. glass.
  - Photograph, 1941 (Box 74)
    Rupert Barneby. Dwight Ripley at Frenchman Flat, May 13, 1941. Taken on the day that Cymopterus ripleyi var. saniculoides was found. Framed copy of black and white photograph.
- Douglas Crase research materials on Dwight Ripley and Rupert Barneby, 1896-2009; Series V
  - Ripley-Barnaby research files
    - People, circa 1940s-2000s (Box 54)
      Aleijadinho (Antônio Francisco Lisboa); J.A. and Rivers—Rivers FNDN (John Ashbery and Larry Rivers); Ashbery to Schuyler; Altmaier (Jakob Altmaier); Auden and Isherwood—Spender (W.H. Auden, Christopher Isherwood, Stephen Spender); Beck (Julian Beck); Bower (Anthony Bower); Botanists—Botanical History; British Poets: Gascoyne, Barker, Thomas, etc.; Burckhardt, Tom; Byron (Robert Byron); Jean Connolly—Cyril Connolly; P.H. Davis: ltrs, etc (Peter Hadland Davis); Denby and Burckhardt (David Denby, Rudy Burckhardt); Deren and Ito (Maya Deren, Teiji Ito)Driberg (Tom Driberg); Effron (Jesse and Lee Effron); Greenberg (Clement Greenberg); Guest (Barbara Guest); Guggenheim—McKinley (Peggy Guggenheim); Hartigan (Grace Hartigan); Hawkins-Kudláček Letters (John Hawkins, Martina Kudláček Heald (Scott Heald); Gerald Heard; Hess (Thomas Hess); Holmgren (Patricia) Holmgren; Brian Howard; John Thomas Howell—ltrs to Dwight and Rupert Howell and Eastwood (John Thomas Howell, Alice Eastwood); Ingwersen (Walter Ingwersen); James, Edward; Jennings, Raine, Madge (Humphrey Jennings, Kathleen Raine, Charles Madge); Koch (Kenneth Koch); Lambert (Constant Lambert); Latouche (John Latouche); Leslie (Alfred Leslie); Liston, Aaron; Lourteig (Alecia Lourteig); Luckow (Melissa Luckow); McEneaney (Sarah McEneaney); Mahler, William; Malina (Judith Malina).
    - People, circa 1940s-2000s (Box 55)
      Marshall, Arthur; Melissa Marshall; Matthews, Jean Flagler; Maas (Willard Maas); Menken Maas (Willard Maas, Marie Menken); Menken File—Anthology Film Archives; Menken and Maas (2 folders) (Willard Maas, Marie Menken); Menken, by Brakhage (Stan Brakhage); Menken by MacDonald (Scott MacDonald); Menken and Warhol—Menken and Albee (Andy Warhol, Edward Albee); Ltrs to Merrill—Washington Univ—Myers, Rivers, Schuyler (James Merrill, John Bernard Myers, Larry Rivers, James Schuyler); Myers, Budd; John Myers (John Bernard Myers); Myers and Hartigan—Syracuse ) (John Bernard Myers, Grace Hartigan); Myers Ltrs—Rivers FNDN (Larry Rivers); Myers to Rivers; Myers to Tibor re: Dwight and Merrill (John Bernard Myers, Tibor de Nagy, James Merrill); Nin and Moré (Anaïs Nin, Gonzalo Moré); Harold Norse; Cyril Norwood (Harrow); O'Hara to Rivers—Rivers Fdn—Eric's CD (Frank O'Hara, Larry Rivers, Eric Brown); Ossorio (Alfonso A. Ossorio); Pease (Roland Pease); Prance, Ghillean—Exchange with Rupert re: Kew; Reveal, James L.; Rivers (Larry Rivers); Rivers on J.A. and John Myers (to FO'H); Rivers to F'OH—Rivers FNDN; Roditi (Édouard Roditi); Sandwith, Noel; Sandwith—Bio, etc.; Scott (Peter Markham Scott); Stamos and Humphrey (Theodoros Stamos, Ralph Humphrey); Tambimuttu (Thurairajah Tambimuttu); Tester—ltrs from Spinney (E.Tester); Dylan Thomas letter; Tibor (Tibor de Nagy); Tibor ltrs; Tibor de Nagy Anthology; Ruthven Todd; Turville-Petre (Francis Turville-Petre); View magazine; Watson, Fouts and the Picasso; Welsh (Stanley L. Welsh); Welsh: Rupert and Pugillus Astragalorum; Williams, Margaret; Winter (Keith Winter).
  - Photographs, 1905-2000
    No Subnote Content
    - Photograph albums, 1905-1973; 4 albums (Box 56)
      England 1905–1928 (3-ring binder); Wappingers Falls, NY, 1943–1949 (3-ring binder); Wappingers Falls and Greenport, NY, 1950–1973 (3-ring binder); England and the Mediterranean, 1929–1937 (3-ring binder); California and the Southwest, 1938–1942 (3-ring binder).
    - Photograph albums, 1938-2000; 4 albums (Box 57)
      California and the Southwest, 1938–1942 (3-ring binder); Rupert after Dwight 1974–2000 (3-ring binder); Carley Brook (3-ring binder); Stirling House Gardens, Greenport, NY (3-ring binder).
    - Mexico, 1960-1969 (Box 58)
      Loose color photographs taken by Dwight Ripley of Mexico.
    - Mexico, 1960-1969 (Box 59)
    - Photographs taken by Dwight and Rupert, 1930-1949; 4 albums (Box 60)
      Albums
    - Photographs, 1930-1949 (Box 75)
      2 albums of photographs taken by Dwight and Rupert, ca. 1930s and 1940s.
  - Books by others and assorted papers, 1896-2004
    - Books, notebooks, and catalogues, 1896-2004 (Box 61)